# HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

#### FOCUS Backend

### **ENGLISH SKILL** ••••

Nam Ho is a senior backend engineer with deep experience working with AWS serverless services and working with mixed teams in Germany and Vietnam. Nam communicates confidently and efficiently with different stakeholders thanks to his experience working on various projects and international teams. He possesses a mastery of the JavaScript/TypeScript technical stack and is well-versed in numerous SQL and NoSQL databases.

## **SKILLS**

#### **LANGUAGES**

JavaScript, TypeScript C# Java PHP

#### **FRAMEWORKS**

Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, Jest Vue.js, Next.js, Vuex AngularJS .NET Laravel, Lumen Bulma

#### **DATABASES**

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle SQL, Microsoft SQL Server MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, DynamoDB Redis

#### **DEVOPS**

Git GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab, SVN CI/CD, Docker Splunk, Kibana SonarCloud

#### **CLOUD**

AWS (Lambda, Step Functions, S3, WAF, NAT, Cognito, EventBridge, SES, SNS, SQS, API Gateway, CloudFront, CloudWatch, SAM, CDK, ElastiCache, VPC, EC2, Kinesis, Batch, CodeBuild, CLI, Transcribe)
Azure Services (App Services, Static Web Apps, Blob Storage, DevOps, Application Insights, Key Vault, Cache for Redis, Database for PostgreSQL)
Google Services (Maps API, Geolocation API, Directions API, OAuth)

#### **LIBRARIES**

jQuery, Bootstrap, io-ts, async, scramjet, Axios, Pinia Swagger, GraphQL AWS SDK Socket.IO BeautifulSoup

# HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

#### **TOOLS**

Postman Puppeteer

#### **OTHER**

Affinda , Sanity , Brevo, CASL, Keycloak, Rockset, RabbitMQ

### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor's degree in Information Technology**

University of Science - Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam 2012 - 2016

## **CERTIFICATES**

#### **AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate**

Amazon Web Services

### **Project Management for Software Engineers (with distinction)**

Mellori Education

2022

# HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

## PROJECT EXPERIENCE

EnBW

#### **NetzeBW**

May 2024 - Ongoing

Industry Energy

Position Team Lead

Team size
6 members

Tech Stack
React.js, Typescript, Jotai,
Axios, Zod, Jest, Nest.js,
KeyCloak, Azure App
Service, Azure Static Web
App, Azure Database for
PostgreSQL, Azure Cache
for Redis, Azure Storage
Account, Azure Application
Insights, Terraform, GitHub
Actions, Azure DevOps.

The project modernizes a web dashboard for managing business data, such as orders and users, while significantly improving performance. The new system integrates with SAP despite its API limitations. The new application features a modern UI, reduced page refreshes, and faster API response times, ultimately enhancing user productivity in business data management.

- Collaborate with the partner's Project Lead and manage the development team in Vietnam.
- Set quality standards for communication, technical documentation, and ticket writing.
- Troubleshoot infrastructure and deployment issues.
- Track overall project progress and individual team members' progress to provide direction and ensure high-quality project delivery.

DWG

#### Konebase

Dec 2023 - Oct 2024

Industry Education

Position Team Lead

Team size
7 members

Tech Stack
ReactJS, Typescript, Nest.js,
Azure Cloud Services (Azure
Service Bus, Azure
Kubernetes Service, Azure
Static Web App, Azure
Application Insights),

The project modernizes the ERP system for a leading German online education university network. The proposed solution enhances user experience, centralizes data, and integrates third-party services while leveraging a modular monolith architecture for scalability.

- Research Debezium, Kafka, and Modular Monolith architecture.
- Document research results and present progress in weekly and monthly catch-ups.
- Assess the technical feasibility of the proposed solution based on scalability, modularity, and complexity.
- Propose Kubernetes for resource management,

## HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

PostgreSQL, Debezium, Terraform, Kafka cost optimization, and seamless cloud provider migration.

anonyfy

## Anonymized recruiting platform

Jul 2023 - Jan 2024

Industry HR Tech

Position Team Lead

Team size
9 members

Link
To the project

Tech Stack
TypeScript, Node.js, Vue.js
v3, Pinia (state
management), AWS (S3, API
Gateway, Lambda,
CloudFront, SQS, SNS, VPC,
WAF, NAT, Cognito,
Transcribe), Google services
(Google OAuth)
CASL (role-based access
control), io-ts (runtime
validation), Affinda (PDF
parsing service), Brevo
(email service provider),
MongoDB Atlas, Swagger

A social platform and tool for anonymous hiring that aims to promote diversity, equity, inclusion and belonging in the workplace. anonyfy helps employers to recruit candidates based on their qualifications, skills and personality, without being influenced by their demographic or personal information.

- Research and design the system architecture
- Prepare technical documentation (High-level system design, Database design, API design, Cost Estimation, Architectural decision, etc.)
- Clarify and estimate the user stories
- Establish project foundation (project structure, libraries, development environment, CI/CD pipeline, quality control tools, etc.)
- Prepare services (AWS, Google services, MongoDB Atlas, Affinda, Brevo) and connect them together
- Control product quality: review pull requests, check SonarCloud reports, check deployment pipeline
- Act like a project manager: distribute tasks, allocate resources, assure communication between development team and PO, and track daily progress
- Develop APIs

HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

HeYo

## Vending machine finder

Dec 2022 - Jul 2023

Industry Commerce

Position
Team Lead,

**Backend Engineer** 

Team size 5 members

Tech Stack
TypeScript, Node.js, Vue.js
v3, Pinia (state
management), Io-ts
(runtime validation),
GraphQL, Sanity (Headless
CMS), SonarCloud, AWS (S3,
API Gateway, Lambda
function, CloudFront,
Cognito), Google services
(Google map API,
Geolocation API, Direction
API, Google OAuth)

A single-page web application that lets users browse, submit and review vending machines in Germany. This project includes three parts: Web application for end users (a desktop version and a mobile PWA version), Management dashboard for internal use (CMS), Data importing web app for internal use.

- Design the system architecture
- Establish project foundation (project structure, libraries, development environment, CI/CD pipeline, quality control tools, etc.)
- Set up services (Sanity CMS, AWS, Google services) and connect them together
- Control product quality
- Act like a project manager: distribute tasks, allocate resources, assure communication between development team and PO, and track daily progress

## HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

Nora Cares GmbH

## Caregiver matching service

Oct 2022 - Jul 2023

Industry Healthcare

Position

**Engineering Coach** 

Team size
6 members

Link

To the project

Tech Stack
TypeScript, Node.js, Jest,
AWS (Lambda, Cognito,
CDK), MongoDB Atlas,
SonarCloud, Bitbucket
Pipeline Template (yaml)

A platform to match and connect care seekers and caregivers. Nam's project mission is to improve the overall project quality by sparring with the product and development team.

- Collaborate with product owner to evaluate ticket effort and sprint estimates
- Review pull requests, current work process as well as existing backend and frontend code base
- Refine work process to achieve project'S objective with high quality and on time
- Set up project quality control and testing tools (SonarCloud, Bitbucket Pipeline)
- Review project's technical documentation

Galeria Karstadt Kaufhof

## **Centralized Product Price Management System**

May 2022 - Now (Support)

Industry

Retail

Position

Delivery Lead (Backend)

Team size

4 members

Tech Stack

TypeScript, Node.js, Lambda, Batch, SQS, SNS, Cognito, MongoDB Atlas, ElastiCache, S3, CDK, scramjet, Rockset, Splunk, SonarCloud, Bitbucket Pipeline Template (yaml) Creation of a centralized price management system for an e-commerce platform. This functions as a single source of truth and collects prices from a wide range of source systems and transfers them in the bundled form to the web shop and other systems.

- Work closely with product owner to break down the business requirements into technical requirements
- Propose and evaluate technical solutions within a complex architecture of microservice
- Communicate with technical teams from other components
- Responsible for delivery, code quality, progress reporting, production system health
- On-call for dealing with urgent unexpected issues on production

CODE LEAP AG, Marie-Curie-Str. 6, 47475 Kamp-Lintfort | HRB 123333 | www.codeleap.de | hello@codeleap.de

# HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

Galeria Karstadt Kaufhof

## **Automated Photo Sample Request Ordering**

Jun 2021 - April 2022

Industry Retail

Position

Delivery Lead (Backend)

Team size

3 members

Tech Stack
TypeScript, Node.js,
DynamoDB, AWS (Lambda,
Step Functions, S3, SES,
SAM, CodeBuild), Qlik,
Splunk

A project about coordination of image processes and photo studios. The software communicates with different modules and destination systems in order to map the photo sample procurement consistently. The frontend app allows end users to manage photo requests and monitor the status of each request.

- Lead the backend services for an app that automatically sends photo samples to different photo studios
- Communicate with technical and nontechnical team members on the project- and client-side
- Collaborate with the German business analysts to discuss and setup complex business logic (inventory, target system, lock, etc.) and requirements
- Request photo samples from central warehouse and various stores (offline) by connecting their inventory systems
- Connect the backend and frontend (Xamarin), Login (AWS Cognito)

Blockhive Vietnam

## **Real Estate Information Management System**

Nov 2020 - May 2021

Industry Proptech

Position

Full-stack engineer

Team size 4 members

Tech Stack
PHP, Lumen, PostgreSQL,
Apache, TypeScript, jQuery,
AWS, Git, PqAdmin, VSCode,

A system that lets real estate agencies get data and display them on a map.

- Develop a RESTful API in PHP (Lumen)
- Create a structure (folder structure, coding convention, base view classes, event emitter feature, utility functions and some frequently used components) for frontend side
- Review and merge the source code of team members
- Deploy the source code to the testing environment and the production environment

CODE LEAP AG, Marie-Curie-Str. 6, 47475 Kamp-Lintfort | HRB 123333 | www.codeleap.de | hello@codeleap.de

HO (he/him)

**Senior Engineer** 

8 Years of Experience

Postman

Blockhive Vietnam

## **Vehicle Position Tracking System**

Mar 2019 - Oct 2020

Industry

Logistics Tech

Position

Lead engineer

Team size **3 members** 

Tech Stack
Java, PostgreSQL, Vue.js,
AngularJS, Git, PgAdmin,
NetBeans, Postman, AWS,
Google Map API, Bootstrap

A system that lets users track the position of a vehicle based on GPS data.

- Lead the main 3 parts of this project: Mobile app (sending GPS data), Backend (receive & process GPS data, and send data to UI via WebSocket) and Frontend (receive data from backend and update the positions on the map)
- Communicate with customers to get requirements, issue reports, daily reports, etc.
- Develop an API to handle management features
- Develop 2 single page UIs, one with Vue.js and another with AngularJS based on clients' requirement
- Deploy the source code to AWS cloud server

Fujinet System

## **Multiple Projects**

Jan 2017 - Mar 2019

Industry ERP

Position

Software engineer

Team size
20 members

Tech Stack C#, Java, Oracle DB, Windows Form, FarPoint Spread Development of ERP systems.

- Create UI and business logic for screens based on customer's requirements for project MITANI with Java and Oracle DB
- Develop an ERP system in C#, Oracle DB, and FarPoint SpreadSheet components for project BATAVIA
- Join some small projects: maintain old ERP systems and manual testing

# NAM HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

Basel Institute on Governance, Swiss (freelancer)

## **Basel Open Intelligence**

2020

Industry Government

Position Full-stack engineer

Team size

3 members

Link

### To the project

Tech Stack
Vue.js, Bulma, Nginx,
Node.js, Express.js,
RabbitMQ, MongoDB,
Elasticsearch, Puppeteers,
pm2, Socket.IO, Memorious,
BeautifulSoup, Git, VSCode,
Postman, Robo3T, Kibana

A web application that collects and shows related data of persons, and organizations on some specific topics as an anti-corruption tool for the government.

- Communicate directly with the client to receive requirements, and propose the technologies and libraries for the app
- Refactor old source code
- Responsible to build backend and frontend of the app
- Build the crawlers to scrape and extract data from some websites for business purposes
- Help the customers to deploy the source code on the production server (CentOS 7)

## CODE\_LEAP

NAM

HO (he/him)

# **Senior Engineer**

8 Years of Experience

#### **RECHTLICHER HINWEIS**

Dieses Profil wurde durch die CODE LEAP AG überreicht. Die hierin übermittelten Daten sind personenbezogene, geschützte Daten im Sinne der DSGVO und der BDSG und somit streng vertraulich und ausschließlich zum Zweck einer Qualifikationsprüfung zu verwenden. Hierin enthaltene Informationen dürfen nicht gespeichert, an Dritte übermittelt, oder für einen anderen, als den hierin bestimmten Zweck genutzt werden. Ein Verstoß ist gem. § 43 BDSG strafbar. Sollte Ihnen der Kandidat bekannt sein, ist es der CODE LEAP AG sofort mitzuteilen. Der Kandidat darf nur mit schriftlicher Zustimmung der CODE LEAP AG beauftragt oder beschäftigt werden.